<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kubevirt.io//feed/releases.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kubevirt.io//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-05T09:50:31+00:00</updated><id>https://kubevirt.io//feed/releases.xml</id><title type="html">KubeVirt.io | Releases</title><subtitle>Virtual Machine Management on Kubernetes</subtitle><entry><title type="html">KubeVirt v1.5.0</title><link href="https://kubevirt.io//2025/changelog-v1.5.0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KubeVirt v1.5.0" /><published>2025-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kubevirt.io//2025/changelog-v1.5.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kubevirt.io//2025/changelog-v1.5.0.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="v150">v1.5.0</h2>

<p>Released on: Thu Mar 13 18:01:18 2025 +0000</p>

<ul>
  <li>[PR #14200][kubevirt-bot] Fetch non-cluster instance type and preferences with namespace key</li>
  <li>[PR #14125][kubevirt-bot] Add entrypoint to the pr-helper for creating the symlink to the multipath socket</li>
  <li>[PR #13942][kubevirt-bot] Instance type and preference runtime data is now stored under <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Status.{Instancetype,Preference}Ref</code> and is no longer mutated into the core VirtualMachine<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"> </code>Spec`.</li>
  <li>[PR #13988][kubevirt-bot] Network interfaces state can be set to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">down</code> or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">up</code> in order to set the link state accordingly when VM is running. Hot plugging of interface in these states is also supported.</li>
  <li>[PR #13985][kubevirt-bot] Interrupted migrations will now be reconciled on next VM start.</li>
  <li>[PR #13936][kubevirt-bot] Updated common-instancetypes bundles to v1.3.0</li>
  <li>[PR #13871][0xFelix] By default the local SSH client on the machine running <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">virtctl ssh</code> is now used. The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">--local-ssh</code> flag is now deprecated.</li>
  <li>[PR #11964][ShellyKa13] VMClone: Remove webhook that checks VM Source</li>
  <li>[PR #13918][0xFelix] <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">type</code> being optional in the syntax of virtctl port-forward/ssh/scp is now deprecated.</li>
  <li>[PR #13838][iholder101] Add the KeepValueUpdated() method to time-defined cache</li>
  <li>[PR #13857][ShellyKa13] VMSnapshot: allow creating snapshot when source doesnt exist yet</li>
  <li>[PR #13864][alromeros] Reject VM clone when source uses backend storage PVC</li>
  <li>[PR #13850][nirdothan] Network interfaces state can be set to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">down</code> or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">up</code> in order to set the link state accordingly.</li>
  <li>[PR #13803][ShellyKa13] BugFix: VMSnapshot: wait for volumes to be bound instead of skip</li>
  <li>[PR #13610][avlitman] Added kubevirt_vm_vnic_info and kubevirt_vmi_vnic_info metrics</li>
  <li>[PR #13642][0xFelix] VMs in a VMPool are able to receive individual configuration through individually indexed ConfigMaps and Secrets.</li>
  <li>[PR #12624][victortoso] Better handle unsupported volume type with Slic table</li>
  <li>[PR #13775][sbrivio-rh] This version of KubeVirt upgrades the passt package, providing user-mode networking, to match upstream version 2025_01_21.4f2c8e7.</li>
  <li>[PR #13717][alicefr] Refuse to volume migrate to legacy datavolumes using no-CSI storageclasses</li>
  <li>[PR #13208][davidvossel] Add VM reset functionality to virtctl and api</li>
  <li>[PR #13817][Barakmor1] The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">AutoResourceLimits</code> feature gate is now deprecated with the feature state graduated to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">GA</code> and thus enabled by default</li>
  <li>[PR #13756][germag] Live migration support for VMIs with (virtiofs) filesystem devices</li>
  <li>[PR #13497][tiraboschi] As an hardening measure (principle of least privilege), the right of creating, editing and deleting <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachineInstanceMigrations</code> are not anymore assigned by default to namespace admins.</li>
  <li>[PR #13777][0xFelix] virtctl: VMs/VMIs with dots in their name are now supported in virtctl portforward, ssh and scp.</li>
  <li>[PR #13713][akalenyu] Enhancement: Declare to libvirt upfront which filesystems are shared to allow migration on some NFS backed provisioners</li>
  <li>[PR #13535][machadovilaca] Collect resource requests and limits from VM instance type/preference</li>
  <li>[PR #13708][orelmisan] Network interfaces’ link state will be reported for interfaces present in VMI spec</li>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>[PR #13428][machadovilaca] Add kubevirt_vmi_migration_(start</td>
          <td>end)_time_seconds metrics</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
  <li>[PR #11266][jean-edouard] KubeVirt will no longer deploy a custom SELinux policy on worker nodes</li>
  <li>[PR #13423][machadovilaca] Add kubevirt_vmi_migration_data_total_bytes metric</li>
  <li>[PR #13699][brianmcarey] Build KubeVirt with go v1.23.4</li>
  <li>[PR #13711][ShellyKa13] VMSnapshot: honor StorageProfile snapshotClass when choosing volumesnapshotclass</li>
  <li>[PR #13667][arnongilboa] Set VM status indication if storage exceeds quota</li>
  <li>[PR #13288][alicefr] Graduation of VolumeUpdateStrategy and VolumeMigration feature gates</li>
  <li>[PR #13520][iholder101] Graduate the clone API to v1beta1 and deprecate v1alpha1</li>
  <li>[PR #11997][jcanocan] Drop <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ExperimentalVirtiofsSupport</code> feature gate in favor of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">EnableVirtioFsConfigVolumes</code> for sharing ConfigMaps, Secrets, DownwardAPI and ServiceAccounts and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">EnableVirtioFsPVC</code> for sharing PVCs.</li>
  <li>[PR #13641][andreabolognani] This version of KubeVirt includes upgraded virtualization technology based on libvirt 10.10.0 and QEMU 9.1.0.</li>
  <li>[PR #13682][alromeros] Bugfix: Support online snapshot of VMs with backend storage</li>
  <li>[PR #13207][alromeros] Bugfix: Support offline snapshot of VMs with backend storage</li>
  <li>[PR #13587][sradco] Alert KubevirtVmHighMemoryUsage has been deprecated.</li>
  <li>[PR #13109][xpivarc] Test suite: 3 new labels are available to filter tests: HostDiskGate, requireHugepages1Gi, blockrwo</li>
  <li>[PR #13110][alicefr] Add the iothreads option to specify number of iothreads to be used</li>
  <li>[PR #13586][akalenyu] storage tests: assemble storage-oriented conformance test suite</li>
  <li>[PR #13606][dasionov] add support for virtio video device for amd64</li>
  <li>[PR #13603][akalenyu] Storage tests: eliminate runtime skips</li>
  <li>[PR #13546][akalenyu] BugFix: Volume hotplug broken with crun &gt;= 1.18</li>
  <li>[PR #13588][Yu-Jack] Ensure virt-tail and virt-monitor have the same timeout, preventing early termination of virt-tail while virt-monitor is still starting</li>
  <li>[PR #13545][alicefr] Upgrade of virt stack</li>
  <li>[PR #13152][akalenyu] VMExport: exported DV uses the storage API</li>
  <li>[PR #13562][kubevirt-bot] Updated common-instancetypes bundles to v1.2.1</li>
  <li>[PR #13496][0xFelix] virtctl expose now uses the unique <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">vm.kubevirt.io/name</code> label found on every virt-launcher Pod as a service selector.</li>
  <li>[PR #13547][0xFelix] virtctl create vm validates disk names and prevents disk names that will lead to rejection of a VM upon creation.</li>
  <li>[PR #13544][jean-edouard] Fixed bug where VMs may not get the persistent EFI they requested</li>
  <li>[PR #13431][avlitman] Add kubevirt_vm_create_date_timestamp_seconds metric</li>
  <li>[PR #13460][alromeros] Bugfix: Support exporting backend PVC</li>
  <li>[PR #13495][brianmcarey] Build KubeVirt with go v1.22.10</li>
  <li>[PR #13437][arnongilboa] Remove deprecated DataVolume garbage collection tests</li>
  <li>[PR #13386][machadovilaca] Ensure IP not empty in kubevirt_vmi_status_addresses metric</li>
  <li>[PR #13424][fossedihelm] Bugfix: fix possible virt-handler race condition and stuck situation during shutdown</li>
  <li>[PR #13458][orelmisan] Adjust managedTap binding to work with VMs with Address Conflict Detection enabled</li>
  <li>[PR #13250][Sreeja1725] Add virt-handler cpu and memory usage metrics</li>
  <li>[PR #13263][jean-edouard] /var/lib/kubelet on the nodes can now be a symlink</li>
  <li>[PR #12705][iholder101] Auto-configured parallel QEMU-level migration threads (a.k.a. multifd)</li>
  <li>[PR #13426][dasionov] bug-fix: prevent status update for old migrations</li>
  <li>[PR #13252][iholder101] Unconditionally disable libvirt’s VMPort feature which is relevant for VMWare only</li>
  <li>[PR #13305][ShellyKa13] VMRestore: remove VMSnapshot logic from vmrestore webhook</li>
  <li>[PR #13367][xpivarc] Bug-fix: Reduced probability of false “failed to detect socket for containerDisk disk0: … connection refused” warnings</li>
  <li>[PR #13243][orelmisan] Dynamic pod interface naming is declared GA</li>
  <li>[PR #13314][EdDev] Network Binding Plugin feature is declared GA</li>
  <li>[PR #13325][machadovilaca] Add node label to migration metrics</li>
  <li>[PR #13294][machadovilaca] Add Guest and Hugepages memory to kubevirt_vm_resource_requests</li>
  <li>[PR #13195][ShellyKa13] Vmrestore - add options to handle cases when target is not ready</li>
  <li>[PR #13138][mhenriks] Avoid NPE when getting filesystem overhead</li>
  <li>[PR #13270][ShellyKa13] VMSnapshot: propagate freeze error failure</li>
  <li>[PR #13148][avlitman] added a new label to kubevirt_vmi_info metric named vmi_pod and contain the current pod name that runs the VMI.</li>
  <li>[PR #12800][alicefr] Enable volume migration for hotplugged volumes</li>
  <li>[PR #12925][0xFelix] virtctl: Image uploads are retried up to 15 times</li>
  <li>[PR #13260][akalenyu] BugFix: VMSnapshot ‘InProgress’ and Failing for a VM with InstanceType and Preference</li>
  <li>[PR #13240][awels] Fix issue starting Virtual Machine Export when succeed/failed VMI exists for that VM</li>
  <li>[PR #12750][lyarwood] The inflexible <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">PreferredUseEFi</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">PreferredUseSecureBoot</code> preference fields have been deprecated ahead of removal in a future version of the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">instancetype.kubevirt.io</code> API. Users should instead use <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">PreferredEfi</code> to provide a preferred <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">EFI</code> configuration for their <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code>.</li>
  <li>[PR #13219][jean-edouard] backend-storage will now correctly use the default virtualization storage class</li>
  <li>[PR #13204][Sreeja1725] Add release v1.4.0 perf and scale benchmarks data</li>
  <li>[PR #13197][akalenyu] BugFix: VMSnapshots broken on OpenShift</li>
  <li>[PR #12765][avlitman] kubevirt_vm_disk_allocated_size_bytes metric added in order to monitor vm sizes</li>
  <li>[PR #12546][Sreeja1725] Update promql query of cpu and memory metrics for sig-performance tests</li>
  <li>[PR #12844][jschintag] Enable virt-exportproxy and virt-exportserver image for s390x</li>
  <li>[PR #12628][ShellyKa13] VMs admitter: remove validation of vm clone volume from the webhook</li>
  <li>[PR #13006][chomatdam] Added labels, annotations to VM Export resources and configurable pod readiness timeout</li>
  <li>[PR #13091][acardace] GA the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VMLiveUpdateFeatures</code> feature-gate.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>kube🤖</name></author><category term="releases" /><category term="release notes" /><category term="changelog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article provides information about KubeVirt release v1.5.0 changes]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KubeVirt v1.4.0</title><link href="https://kubevirt.io//2024/changelog-v1.4.0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KubeVirt v1.4.0" /><published>2024-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kubevirt.io//2024/changelog-v1.4.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kubevirt.io//2024/changelog-v1.4.0.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="v140">v1.4.0</h2>

<p>Released on: Wed Nov 13 08:14:06 2024 +0000</p>

<ul>
  <li>[PR #13225][kubevirt-bot] backend-storage will now correctly use the default virtualization storage class</li>
  <li>[PR #13203][kubevirt-bot] BugFix: VMSnapshots broken on OpenShift</li>
  <li>[PR #13071][machadovilaca] Add kubevirt_vm_resource_limits metric</li>
  <li>[PR #13090][acardace] Allow live updating VMs’ tolerations</li>
  <li>[PR #12629][jean-edouard] backend-storage now supports RWO FS</li>
  <li>[PR #13086][lyarwood] A new <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">spec.configuration.instancetype.referencePolicy</code> configurable has been added to the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">KubeVirt</code> CR with support for <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">reference</code> (default), <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">expand</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">expandAll</code> policies provided.</li>
  <li>[PR #13064][xpivarc] Fix cache corruption</li>
  <li>[PR #12967][xpivarc] BochsDisplayForEFIGuests is GAed, use  “kubevirt.io/vga-display-efi-x86” annotation on Kubevirt CR before upgrading in case you need retain compatibility.</li>
  <li>[PR #13078][qinqon] Add dynamic pod interface name feature gate</li>
  <li>[PR #13072][0xFelix] virtctl: virtctl create vm can now use the Access Credentials API to add credentials to a new VM</li>
  <li>[PR #13050][vamsikrishna-siddu] fix the cpu model issue for s390x.</li>
  <li>[PR #12802][machadovilaca] Add kubevirt_vmi_status_addresses metric</li>
  <li>[PR #13027][awels] BugFix: Stop creating tokenSecretRef when no volumes to export</li>
  <li>[PR #13001][awels] Relaxed check on modify VM spec during VM snapshot to only check disks/volumes</li>
  <li>[PR #13082][kubevirt-bot] Updated common-instancetypes bundles to v1.2.0</li>
  <li>[PR #12601][mhenriks] vmsnapshot: Enable status subresource for snapshot.kubevirt.io api group</li>
  <li>[PR #13018][orelmisan] Support Dynamic Primary Pod NIC Name</li>
  <li>[PR #13019][0xFelix] virtctl: The flags <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">--volume-clone-pvc</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">--volume-datasource</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">--volume-blank</code> are deprecated in favor of the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">--volume-import</code> flag.</li>
  <li>[PR #13059][EdDev] Network hotplug feature is declared as GA.</li>
  <li>[PR #13024][EdDev] network binding plugin: Introduce a new <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">managedTap</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">domainAttachmentType</code></li>
  <li>[PR #13060][EdDev] Network binding plugins feature is declared as Beta.</li>
  <li>[PR #13045][dasionov] Add ‘machine_type’ label for kubevirt_vm_info metric</li>
  <li>[PR #13030][alicefr] Removed the ManualRecoveryRequired field from the VolumeMigrationState and convert it to the VM condition ManualRecoveryRequired</li>
  <li>[PR #13053][0xFelix] virtctl: Users can specify a sysprep volume in VMs created with virtctl create vm</li>
  <li>[PR #12855][0xFelix] virtctl expose: Drop flag to set deprecated LoadBalancerIP option</li>
  <li>[PR #13008][0xFelix] virtctl: Allow creating a basic cloud-init config with virtctl create vm</li>
  <li>[PR #12829][0xFelix] fix: Proxies configured in kubeconfig are used in client-go for asynchronous subresources like VNC or Console</li>
  <li>[PR #12733][alromeros] Bugfix: Fix disk expansion logic by checking usable size instead of requested capacity</li>
  <li>[PR #13052][fossedihelm] Update code-generators to 1.31.1</li>
  <li>[PR #12882][brianmcarey] Build KubeVirt with go v1.22.8</li>
  <li>[PR #13040][awels] BugFix: Allow VMExport to work with VM columes that have dots in its name</li>
  <li>[PR #12729][fossedihelm] Update k8s dependencies to 0.31.0</li>
  <li>[PR #12867][jschintag] Fixed additional broken amd64 image in some image manifests</li>
  <li>[PR #12940][Barakmor1] Deprecate the DockerSELinuxMCS FeatureGate</li>
  <li>[PR #12943][Barakmor1] The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">GPU</code> feature gate is now deprecated with the feature state graduated to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">GA</code> and thus enabled by default</li>
  <li>[PR #12992][machadovilaca] Add a ‘outdated’ label to kubevirt_vmi_info metric</li>
  <li>[PR #12933][ShellyKa13] VM admitter: improve validation of vm spec datavolumetemplate</li>
  <li>[PR #12986][lyarwood] The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">PreferredEfi</code> preference is now only applied when a user has not already enabled either <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">EFI</code> or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">BIOS</code> within the underlying <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code>.</li>
  <li>[PR #12117][Sreeja1725] Integrate kwok with sig-scale tests</li>
  <li>[PR #12716][Sreeja1725] Update kubevirt_rest_client_request_latency_seconds to count list calls if made using query params</li>
  <li>[PR #12578][dasionov] Mark Running field as deprecated</li>
  <li>[PR #12753][lyarwood] The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">CommonInstancetypesDeploymentGate</code> feature gate and underlying feature are graduated to GA and now always enabled by default. A single new <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">KubeVirt</code> configurable is also introduced to allow cluster admins a way of explicitly disabling deployment when required.</li>
  <li>[PR #12645][avlitman] Add kubevirt_vmsnapshot_succeeded_timestamp_seconds metric</li>
  <li>[PR #11097][vamsikrishna-siddu] add s390x support for kubevirt builder</li>
  <li>[PR #12910][machadovilaca] Rename kubevirt_vm_resource_requests ‘vmi’ label to ‘name’</li>
  <li>[PR #12848][iholder101] Reduce default CompletionTimeoutPerGiB from 800s to 150s</li>
  <li>[PR #12861][ShellyKa13] bugfix: fix possible miss update of datavolumename on vmrestore restores</li>
  <li>[PR #12441][machadovilaca] Increase periodicity in domainstats migration metrics</li>
  <li>[PR #12718][machadovilaca] Add kubevirt_vm_info metric</li>
  <li>[PR #12599][xpivarc] MaxCpuSockets won’t block creation of VMs with more Sockets than MaxCpuSockets declare</li>
  <li>[PR #12857][akalenyu] BugFix: Fail to create VMExport via virtctl vmexport create</li>
  <li>[PR #12355][alicefr] Add the volume migration state in the VM status</li>
  <li>[PR #12726][awels] Concurrent addvolume/removevolume using virtctl no longer fail if concurrent modifications happen</li>
  <li>[PR #12835][ShellyKa13] bugfix: In case of err in vmrestore, leave VM without RestoreInProgress annotation allowing it to be started</li>
  <li>[PR #12809][dasionov] bug-fix: Ensure PDB associated with a VMI is deleted when it Reaches Succeeded or Failed phase</li>
  <li>[PR #12813][akalenyu] BugFix: can’t create export pod on OpenShift</li>
  <li>[PR #12786][0xFelix] virtctl: Created VMs can infer an instancetype or preference from PVC, Registry and Snapshot sources now.</li>
  <li>[PR #12764][ShellyKa13] bugfix: vmrestore create DVs before creation/update of restored VM</li>
  <li>[PR #10562][dhiller] Continue changes to Ginkgo V2 Serial runs</li>
  <li>[PR #12516][vamsikrishna-siddu] enable initial e2e tests for s390x.</li>
  <li>[PR #12739][lyarwood] A new <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">PreferredEfi</code> field has been added to preferences to express the preferred <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">EFI</code> configuration for a given <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code>.</li>
  <li>[PR #12737][machadovilaca] Add evictable label to kubevirt_vmi_info</li>
  <li>[PR #12232][lyarwood] The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">NUMA</code> feature gate is now deprecated with the feature state graduated to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">GA</code> and thus enabled by default</li>
  <li>[PR #12582][mhenriks] vmsnapshot: when checking if a VM is running, ignore runStrategy</li>
  <li>[PR #12625][machadovilaca] Add kubevirt_vm_resource_requests for CPU resource</li>
  <li>[PR #12605][mhenriks] vmexport: enable status subresource for VirtualMachineExport</li>
  <li>[PR #12616][orenc1] replace <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Update()</code> with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Patch()</code> for <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">test VirtualMachineInstancesPerNode</code></li>
  <li>[PR #12557][codingben] Optionally create data source using virtctl image upload.</li>
  <li>[PR #12547][mhenriks] virt-api: skip clone auth check when DataVolume already exists</li>
  <li>[PR #12613][orelmisan] Bridge binding: Static routes to subnets containing the pod’s NIC IP address are passed to the VM.</li>
  <li>[PR #12594][tiraboschi] [tests] introduce a decorator for Periodic_only tests</li>
  <li>[PR #12593][machadovilaca] Add kubevirt_vm_resource_requests metric for memory resource</li>
  <li>[PR #12617][Acedus] grpc from go.mod is now correctly shipped in release images</li>
  <li>[PR #12638][akalenyu] BugFix: “Cannot allocate memory” warnings for containerdisk VMs</li>
  <li>[PR #12395][alicefr] Add new condition for VMIStorageLiveMigratable</li>
  <li>[PR #12419][nunnatsa] Add timeout to validation webhooks</li>
  <li>[PR #12592][awels] Fixed issue emitting created secret events when not actually creating secrets during VMExport setup</li>
  <li>[PR #12584][brianmcarey] Build KubeVirt with go v1.22.6</li>
  <li>[PR #12575][Barakmor1] Advise users to use RunStrategy in virt-api messages</li>
  <li>[PR #12466][orenc1] tests/vm_tests.go: replace Update() with Patch()</li>
  <li>[PR #12548][kubevirt-bot] Updated common-instancetypes bundles to v1.1.0</li>
  <li>[PR #12476][jschintag] Enable live-migration and node labels on s390x</li>
  <li>[PR #12194][mhenriks] VM supports kubevirt.io/immediate-data-volume-creation: “false” which delays creating DataVolumeTemplates until VM is started</li>
  <li>[PR #11802][matthewei] Adding newMacAddresses validatewebhook for  VMCloneAPI</li>
  <li>[PR #11754][nickolaev] Adding support for the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">igb</code> network interface model</li>
  <li>[PR #12254][jkinred] * Reduced the severity of log messages when a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VolumeSnapshotClass</code> is not found. When snapshots are not enabled for a volume, the reason will still be displayed in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">status.volumeSnapshotStatuses</code> field of a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code> resource.</li>
  <li>[PR #12460][mhenriks] virt-api: unencode authorization extra headers</li>
  <li>[PR #12451][fossedihelm] Fix: eviction requests to completed virt-launcher pods cannot trigger a live migration</li>
  <li>[PR #11881][lyarwood] The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">expand-spec</code> subresource API now applies defaults to the returned <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code> to ensure the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachineInstanceSpec</code> within is closer to the eventual version used when starting the original <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code>.</li>
  <li>[PR #12452][andreabolognani] This version of KubeVirt includes upgraded virtualization technology based on libvirt 10.5.0 and QEMU 9.0.0.</li>
  <li>[PR #12425][fudancoder] fix some comments</li>
  <li>[PR #12354][qinqon] Use optional interface at passt binding sidecar</li>
  <li>[PR #12268][fossedihelm] Drop <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ForceRestart</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ForceStop</code> methods from client-go</li>
  <li>[PR #12235][orelmisan] Network binding plugins: Enable the ability to specify compute memory overhead</li>
  <li>[PR #12209][orenc1] Fix wrong KubeVirtVMIExcessiveMigrations alert calculation in an upgrade scenario.</li>
  <li>[PR #12261][fossedihelm] Fix: persistent tpm can be used with vmis containing dots in their name</li>
  <li>[PR #12247][Sreeja1725] Add perf-scale benchmarks for release v1.3</li>
  <li>[PR #12181][akalenyu] BugFix: Grant namespace admin RBAC to passthrough a client USB to a VMI</li>
  <li>[PR #12096][machadovilaca] Fix missing performance metrics for VMI resources</li>
  <li>[PR #11856][Sreeja1725] Add unit tests to check for API backward compatibility</li>
  <li>[PR #12116][Sreeja1725] Add CPU/Memory utilization of components metrics to kubevirt benchmarks</li>
  <li>[PR #12195][awels] Virt export route has an edge termination of redirect</li>
  <li>[PR #12212][acardace] enable only for VMs with memory &gt;= 1Gi</li>
  <li>[PR #12053][vladikr] Only a single vgpu display option with ramfb will be configured per VMI.</li>
  <li>[PR #12193][acardace] fix RerunOnFailure stuck in Provisioning</li>
  <li>[PR #12186][kubevirt-bot] Updated common-instancetypes bundles to v1.0.1</li>
  <li>[PR #12180][0xFelix] VMs with a single socket and NetworkInterfaceMultiqueue enabled require a restart to hotplug additional CPU sockets.</li>
  <li>[PR #11927][lyarwood] All <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">preferredCPUTopology</code> constants prefixed with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Prefer</code> have been deprecated and will be removed in a future version of the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">instancetype.kubevirt.io</code> API.</li>
  <li>[PR #12169][lyarwood] <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">PreferredDiskDedicatedIoThread</code> is now only applied to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">virtio</code> disk devices</li>
  <li>[PR #12125][ksimon1] chore: bump virtio-win image version to 0.1.248</li>
  <li>[PR #12128][acardace] Memory Hotplug fixes and stabilization</li>
  <li>[PR #11911][alromeros] Bugfix: Implement retry mechanism in export server and vmexport</li>
  <li>[PR #11982][RamLavi] Introduce validatingAdmissionPolicy to restrict node patches on virt-handler</li>
  <li>[PR #12119][acardace] Fix VMPools when <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">LiveUpdate</code> as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">vmRolloutStrategy</code> is used.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>kube🤖</name></author><category term="releases" /><category term="release notes" /><category term="changelog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article provides information about KubeVirt release v1.4.0 changes]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KubeVirt v1.3.0</title><link href="https://kubevirt.io//2024/changelog-v1.3.0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KubeVirt v1.3.0" /><published>2024-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kubevirt.io//2024/changelog-v1.3.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kubevirt.io//2024/changelog-v1.3.0.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="v130">v1.3.0</h2>

<p>Released on: Wed Jul 17 15:09:44 2024 +0000</p>

<ul>
  <li>[PR #12319][Sreeja1725] Add v1.3.0 perf and scale benchmarks data</li>
  <li>[PR #12330][kubevirt-bot] Fix wrong KubeVirtVMIExcessiveMigrations alert calculation in an upgrade scenario.</li>
  <li>[PR #12328][acardace] enable only for VMs with memory &gt;= 1Gi</li>
  <li>[PR #12272][Sreeja1725] Add unit tests to check for API backward compatibility</li>
  <li>[PR #12296][orelmisan] Network binding plugins: Enable the ability to specify compute memory overhead</li>
  <li>[PR #12279][kubevirt-bot] Fix: persistent tpm can be used with vmis containing dots in their name</li>
  <li>[PR #12226][kubevirt-bot] Virt export route has an edge termination of redirect</li>
  <li>[PR #12240][kubevirt-bot] Updated common-instancetypes bundles to v1.0.1</li>
  <li>[PR #12249][kubevirt-bot] Fix missing performance metrics for VMI resources</li>
  <li>[PR #12237][vladikr] Only a single vgpu display option with ramfb will be configured per VMI.</li>
  <li>[PR #12122][kubevirt-bot] Fix VMPools when <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">LiveUpdate</code> as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">vmRolloutStrategy</code> is used.</li>
  <li>[PR #12201][kubevirt-bot] fix RerunOnFailure stuck in Provisioning</li>
  <li>[PR #12151][kubevirt-bot] Bugfix: Implement retry mechanism in export server and vmexport</li>
  <li>[PR #12171][kubevirt-bot] <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">PreferredDiskDedicatedIoThread</code> is now only applied to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">virtio</code> disk devices</li>
  <li>[PR #12146][kubevirt-bot] Memory Hotplug fixes and stabilization</li>
  <li>[PR #12185][kubevirt-bot] VMs with a single socket and NetworkInterfaceMultiqueue enabled require a restart to hotplug additional CPU sockets.</li>
  <li>[PR #12132][kubevirt-bot] Introduce validatingAdmissionPolicy to restrict node patches on virt-handler</li>
  <li>[PR #12109][acardace] Support Memory Hotplug with Hugepages</li>
  <li>[PR #12009][xpivarc] By enabling NodeRestriction feature gate, Kubevirt now authorize virt-handler’s requests to modify VMs.</li>
  <li>[PR #11681][lyarwood] The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">CommonInstancetypesDeployment</code> feature and gate are retrospectively moved to Beta from the 1.2.0 release.</li>
  <li>[PR #12025][fossedihelm] Add descheduler compatibility</li>
  <li>[PR #12097][fossedihelm] Bump k8s deps to 0.30.0</li>
  <li>[PR #12089][jean-edouard] Less privileged virt-operator ClusterRole</li>
  <li>[PR #12064][akalenyu] BugFix: Graceful deletion skipped for any delete call to the VM (not VMI) resource</li>
  <li>[PR #10490][jschintag] Add support for building and running kubevirt on s390x.</li>
  <li>[PR #12079][EdDev] Network hotplug feature is declared as Beta.</li>
  <li>[PR #11455][lyarwood] <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">LiveUpdates</code>  of VMs using instance types are now supported with the same caveats as when making changes to a vanilla VM.</li>
  <li>[PR #12000][machadovilaca] Create kubevirt_vmi_launcher_memory_overhead_bytes metric</li>
  <li>[PR #11915][ormergi] The ‘passt’ core network binding is discontinued and removed.</li>
  <li>[PR #12016][acardace] fix starting VM with Manual RunStrategy</li>
  <li>[PR #11533][alicefr] Implement volume migration and introduce the migration updateVolumesStrategy field</li>
  <li>[PR #11934][assafad] Add kubevirt_vmi_last_connection_timestamp_seconds metric</li>
  <li>[PR #11956][mhenriks] Introduce export.kibevirt.io/v1beta1</li>
  <li>[PR #11996][ShellyKa13] BugFix: Fix restore panic in case of volumesnapshot missing</li>
  <li>[PR #11957][mhenriks] snapshot: Ignore unfreeze error if VMSnapshot deleting</li>
  <li>[PR #11906][machadovilaca] Create kubevirt_vmi_info metric</li>
  <li>[PR #11969][iholder101] Infra components control-plane nodes NoSchedule toleration</li>
  <li>[PR #11955][mhenriks] Introduce snapshot.kibevirt.io/v1beta1</li>
  <li>[PR #11883][orelmisan] Restart of a VM is required when the CPU socket count is reduced</li>
  <li>[PR #11835][talcoh2x] add Intel Gaudi to adopters.</li>
  <li>[PR #11344][aerosouund] Refactor device plugins to use a base plugin and define a common interface</li>
  <li>[PR #11973][fossedihelm] Bug fix: Correctly reflect RestartRequired condition</li>
  <li>[PR #11963][acardace] Fix RerunOnFailure RunStrategy</li>
  <li>[PR #11962][lyarwood] <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachines</code> referencing an instance type are now allowed when the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">LiveUpdate</code> feature is enabled and will trigger the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">RestartRequired</code> condition if the reference within the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code> is changed.</li>
  <li>[PR #11942][ido106] Update virtctl to use v1beta1 endpoint for both regular and async image upload</li>
  <li>[PR #11648][kubevirt-bot] Updated common-instancetypes bundles to v1.0.0</li>
  <li>[PR #11659][iholder101] Require scheduling infra components onto control-plane nodes</li>
  <li>[PR #10545][lyarwood] <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ControllerRevisions</code> containing instance types and preferences are now upgraded to their latest available version when the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code> owning them is resync’d by <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">virt-controller</code>.</li>
  <li>[PR #11901][EdDev] The ‘macvtap’ core network binding is discontinued and removed.</li>
  <li>[PR #11922][alromeros] Bugfix: Fix VM manifest rendering in export controller</li>
  <li>[PR #11908][victortoso] sidecar-shim: allow stderr log from binary hooks</li>
  <li>[PR #11729][lyarwood] <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">spreadOptions</code> have been introduced to preferences in order to allow for finer grain control of the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">preferSpread</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">preferredCPUTopology</code>. This includes the ability to now spread vCPUs across guest visible sockets, cores and threads.</li>
  <li>[PR #11655][acardace] Allow to hotplug vcpus for VMs with CPU requests and/or limits set</li>
  <li>[PR #11701][EdDev] The SLIRP core binding is deprecated and removed.</li>
  <li>[PR #11773][jean-edouard] Persistent TPM/UEFI will use the default storage class if none is specified in the CR.</li>
  <li>[PR #11846][victortoso] SMBios sidecar can be built out-of-tree</li>
  <li>[PR #11788][ormergi] The network-info annotation is now used for mapping between SR-IOV network and the underlying device PCI address</li>
  <li>[PR #11700][alicefr] Add the updateVolumeStrategy field</li>
  <li>[PR #11256][andreabolognani] This version of KubeVirt includes upgraded virtualization technology based on libvirt 10.0.0 and QEMU 8.2.0.</li>
  <li>[PR #11482][brianmcarey] Build KubeVirt with go v1.22.2</li>
  <li>[PR #11641][alicefr] Add kubevirt.io/testWorkloadUpdateMigrationAbortion annotation and a mechanism to abort workload updates</li>
  <li>[PR #11770][alicefr] Fix the live updates for volumes and disks</li>
  <li>[PR #11790][aburdenthehand] Re-adding Cloudflare to our ADOPTERS list</li>
  <li>[PR #11718][fossedihelm] Fix: SEV methods in client-go now satisfy the proxy server configuration, if provided</li>
  <li>[PR #11685][fossedihelm] Updated go version of the client-go to 1.21</li>
  <li>[PR #11618][AlonaKaplan] Extend network binding plugin to support device-info DownwardAPI.</li>
  <li>[PR #11283][assafad] Collect VMI OS info from the Guest agent as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kubevirt_vmi_phase_count</code> metric labels</li>
  <li>[PR #11676][machadovilaca] Rename rest client metrics to include kubevirt prefix</li>
  <li>[PR #11557][avlitman] New memory statistics added named kubevirt_memory_delta_from_requested_bytes</li>
  <li>[PR #11678][Vicente-Cheng] Improve the handling of ordinal pod interface name for upgrade</li>
  <li>[PR #11653][EdDev] Build the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">passt</code>custom CNI binary statically, for the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">passt</code> network binding plugin.</li>
  <li>[PR #11294][machadovilaca] Fix kubevirt_vm_created_total being broken down by virt-api pod</li>
  <li>[PR #11307][machadovilaca] Add e2e tests for metrics</li>
  <li>[PR #11479][vladikr] virtual machines instance will no longer be stuck in an irrecoverable state after an interrupted postcopy migration. Instead, these will fail and could be restarted again.</li>
  <li>[PR #11416][dhiller] emission of k8s logs when using programmatic focus with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">FIt</code></li>
  <li>[PR #11272][dharmit] Make ‘image’ field in hook sidecar annotation optional.</li>
  <li>[PR #11500][iholder101] Support HyperV Passthrough: automatically use all available HyperV features</li>
  <li>[PR #11484][jcanocan] Reduce the downwardMetrics server maximum number of request per second to 1.</li>
  <li>[PR #11498][acardace] Allow to hotplug memory for VMs with memory limits set</li>
  <li>[PR #11470][brianmcarey] Build KubeVirt with Go version 1.21.8</li>
  <li>[PR #11312][alromeros] Improve handling of export resources in virtctl vmexport</li>
  <li>[PR #11367][alromeros] Bugfix: Allow vmexport download redirections by printing logs into stderr</li>
  <li>[PR #11219][alromeros] Bugfix: Improve handling of IOThreads with incompatible buses</li>
  <li>[PR #11149][0xFelix] virtctl: It is possible to import volumes from GCS when creating a VM now</li>
  <li>[PR #11404][avlitman] KubeVirtComponentExceedsRequestedCPU and KubeVirtComponentExceedsRequestedMemory alerts are deprecated; they do not indicate a genuine issue.</li>
  <li>[PR #11331][anjuls] add cloudraft to adopters.</li>
  <li>[PR #11387][alaypatel07] add perf-scale benchmarks for release v1.2</li>
  <li>[PR #11095][ShellyKa13] Expose volumesnapshot error in vmsnapshot object</li>
  <li>[PR #11372][xpivarc] Bug-fix: Fix nil panic if VM update fails</li>
  <li>[PR #11267][mhenriks] BugFix: Ensure DataVolumes created by virt-controller (DataVolumeTemplates) are recreated and owned by the VM in the case of DR and backup/restore.</li>
  <li>[PR #10900][KarstenB] BugFix: Fixed incorrect APIVersion of APIResourceList</li>
  <li>[PR #11306][fossedihelm] fix(ksm): set the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kubevirt.io/ksm-enabled</code> node label to true if the ksm is managed by KubeVirt, instead of reflect the actual ksm value.</li>
  <li>[PR #11330][jean-edouard] More information in the migration state of VMI / migration objects</li>
  <li>[PR #11264][machadovilaca] Fix perfscale buckets error</li>
  <li>[PR #11183][dhiller] Extend OWNERS for sig-buildsystem</li>
  <li>[PR #11058][fossedihelm] fix(vmclone): delete vmclone resource when the target vm is deleted</li>
  <li>[PR #11265][xpivarc] Bug fix: VM controller doesn’t corrupt its cache anymore</li>
  <li>[PR #11205][akalenyu] Fix migration breaking in case the VM has an rng device after hotplugging a block volume on cgroupsv2</li>
  <li>[PR #11051][alromeros] Bugfix: Improve error reporting when fsfreeze fails</li>
  <li>[PR #11156][nunnatsa] Move some verification from the VMI create validation webhook to the CRD</li>
  <li>[PR #11146][RamLavi] node-labeller: Remove obsolete functionalities</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>kube🤖</name></author><category term="releases" /><category term="release notes" /><category term="changelog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article provides information about KubeVirt release v1.3.0 changes]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KubeVirt v1.2.0</title><link href="https://kubevirt.io//2024/changelog-v1.2.0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KubeVirt v1.2.0" /><published>2024-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kubevirt.io//2024/changelog-v1.2.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kubevirt.io//2024/changelog-v1.2.0.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="v120">v1.2.0</h2>

<p>Released on: Tue Mar 5 20:25:04 2024 +0000</p>

<ul>
  <li>[PR #11318][fossedihelm] fix(vmclone): delete vmclone resource when the target vm is deleted</li>
  <li>[PR #11393][kubevirt-bot] Bug-fix: Fix nil panic if VM update fails</li>
  <li>[PR #11354][kubevirt-bot] Fix perfscale buckets error</li>
  <li>[PR #11378][fossedihelm] fix(ksm): set the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kubevirt.io/ksm-enabled</code> node label to true if the ksm is managed by KubeVirt, instead of reflect the actual ksm value.</li>
  <li>[PR #11271][kubevirt-bot] Bug fix: VM controller doesn’t corrupt its cache anymore</li>
  <li>[PR #11242][kubevirt-bot] Fix migration breaking in case the VM has an rng device after hotplugging a block volume on cgroupsv2</li>
  <li>[PR #11144][0xFelix] virtctl: Specifying size when creating a VM and using –volume-import to clone a PVC or a VolumeSnapshot is optional now</li>
  <li>[PR #11054][jean-edouard] New cluster-wide <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">vmRolloutStrategy</code> setting to define whether changes to VMs should either be always staged or live-updated when possible.</li>
  <li>[PR #11064][AlonaKaplan] Introduce a new API to mark a binding plugin as migratable.</li>
  <li>[PR #11122][brianmcarey] Update runc dependency to v1.1.12</li>
  <li>[PR #10982][machadovilaca] Refactor monitoring metrics</li>
  <li>[PR #11069][ormergi] Bug fix: Packet drops during the initial phase of VM live migration https://issues.redhat.com/browse/CNV-28040</li>
  <li>[PR #10961][jcanocan] Reduced VM rescheduling time on node failure</li>
  <li>[PR #11065][fossedihelm] fix(vmclone): Generate VM patches from vmsnapshotcontent, instead of current VM</li>
  <li>[PR #10888][fossedihelm] [Bugfix] Clone VM with WaitForFirstConsumer binding mode PVC now works.</li>
  <li>[PR #11068][brianmcarey] Update container base image to use current stable debian 12 base</li>
  <li>[PR #11047][jschintag] Fix potential crash when trying to list USB devices on host without any</li>
  <li>[PR #10970][alromeros] Expose fs disk information via GuestOsInfo</li>
  <li>[PR #11050][fossedihelm] restrict default cluster role to authenticated only users</li>
  <li>[PR #11025][0xFelix] Allow unprivileged users read-only access to VirtualMachineCluster{Instancetypes,Preferences} by default.</li>
  <li>[PR #10853][machadovilaca] Refactor monitoring collectors</li>
  <li>[PR #11001][fossedihelm] Allow <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kubevirt.io:default</code> clusterRole to get,list kubevirts</li>
  <li>[PR #10905][tiraboschi] Aggregate DVs conditions on VMI (and so VM)</li>
  <li>[PR #10963][alromeros] Bugfix: Reject volume exports when no output is specified</li>
  <li>[PR #10962][machadovilaca] Update monitoring file structure</li>
  <li>[PR #10981][AlonaKaplan] Report IP of interfaces using network binding plugin.</li>
  <li>[PR #10922][kubevirt-bot] Updated common-instancetypes bundles to v0.4.0</li>
  <li>[PR #10914][brianmcarey] KubeVirt is now built with go 1.21.5</li>
  <li>[PR #10846][RamLavi] Change vm.status.PrintableStatus default value to “Stopped”</li>
  <li>[PR #10787][matthewei] # Create a manifest for a clone with template label filters:</li>
  <li>[PR #10918][orelmisan] VMClone: Emit an event in case restore creation fails</li>
  <li>[PR #10916][orelmisan] Fix the value of VMI <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Status.GuestOSInfo.Version</code></li>
  <li>[PR #10924][AlonaKaplan] Deprecate macvtap</li>
  <li>[PR #10898][matthewei] vmi status’s guestOsInfo adds <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Machine</code></li>
  <li>[PR #10866][AlonaKaplan] Raise an error in case passt feature gate or API are used.</li>
  <li>[PR #10879][brianmcarey] Built with golang 1.20.12</li>
  <li>[PR #10872][RamLavi] IsolateEmulatorThread: Add cluster-wide parity completion setting</li>
  <li>[PR #10700][machadovilaca] Refactor monitoring alerts</li>
  <li>[PR #10839][RamLavi] Change second emulator thread assign strategy to best-effort.</li>
  <li>[PR #10863][dhiller] Remove year from generated code copyright</li>
  <li>[PR #10747][acardace] Fix KubeVirt for CRIO 1.28 by using checksums to verify containerdisks when migrating VMIs</li>
  <li>[PR #10860][akalenyu] BugFix: Double cloning with filter fails</li>
  <li>[PR #10567][awels] Attachment pod creation is now rate limited</li>
  <li>[PR #10845][orelmisan] Reject VirtualMachineClone creation when target name is equal to source name</li>
  <li>[PR #10840][acardace] Requests/Limits can now be configured when using CPU/Memory hotplug</li>
  <li>[PR #10418][machadovilaca] Add total VMs created metric</li>
  <li>[PR #10800][AlonaKaplan] Support macvtap as a binding plugin</li>
  <li>[PR #10753][victortoso] Fixes device permission when using USB host passthrough</li>
  <li>[PR #10774][victortoso] Windows offline activation with ACPI SLIC table</li>
  <li>[PR #10783][RamLavi] Support multiple CPUs in Housekeeping cgroup</li>
  <li>[PR #10809][orelmisan] Source virt-launcher: Log migration info by default</li>
  <li>[PR #10046][victortoso] Add v1alpha3 for hooks</li>
  <li>[PR #10651][machadovilaca] Refactor monitoring  recording-rules</li>
  <li>[PR #10732][AlonaKaplan] Extend kubvirt CR by adding domain attachment option to the network binding plugin API.</li>
  <li>[PR #10244][hshitomi] Added “adm” subcommand under “virtctl”, and “log-verbosity” subcommand under “adm”. The log-verbosity command is:</li>
  <li>[PR #10658][matthewei] 1. Support “Clone API” to filter VirtualMachine.spec.template.annotation and VirtualMachine.spec.template.label</li>
  <li>[PR #10593][RamLavi] Fixes SMT Alignment Error in virt-launcher pod by optimizing isolateEmulatorThread feature (BZ#2228103).</li>
  <li>[PR #10720][awels] Restored hotplug attachment pod request/limit to original value</li>
  <li>[PR #10657][germag] Exposing Filesystem Persistent Volumes (PVs)  to the VM using unprivilege virtiofsd.</li>
  <li>[PR #10637][dharmit] Functional tests for sidecar hook with ConfigMap</li>
  <li>[PR #10598][alicefr] Add PVC option to the hook sidecars for supplying additional debugging tools</li>
  <li>[PR #10526][cfilleke]</li>
  <li>[PR #10699][qinqon] virt-launcher: fix qemu non root log path</li>
  <li>[PR #10689][akalenyu] BugFix: cgroupsv2 device allowlist is bound to virt-handler internal state/block disk device overwritten on hotplug</li>
  <li>[PR #10693][machadovilaca] Remove MigrateVmiDiskTransferRateMetric</li>
  <li>[PR #10615][orelmisan] Remove leftover NonRoot feature gate</li>
  <li>[PR #10529][alromeros] Allow LUN disks to be hotplugged</li>
  <li>[PR #10582][orelmisan] Remove leftover NonRootExperimental feature gate</li>
  <li>[PR #10596][mhenriks] Disable HTTP/2 to mitigate CVE-2023-44487</li>
  <li>[PR #10570][machadovilaca] Fix LowKVMNodesCount not firing</li>
  <li>[PR #10571][tiraboschi] vmi memory footprint increase by 35M when guest serial console logging is turned on (default on).</li>
  <li>[PR #10425][ormergi] Introduce network binding plugin for Passt networking, interfacing with Kubevirt new network binding plugin API.</li>
  <li>[PR #10479][dharmit] Ability to run scripts through hook sidecar</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>kube🤖</name></author><category term="releases" /><category term="release notes" /><category term="changelog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article provides information about KubeVirt release v1.2.0 changes]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KubeVirt v1.1.0</title><link href="https://kubevirt.io//2023/changelog-v1.1.0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KubeVirt v1.1.0" /><published>2023-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kubevirt.io//2023/changelog-v1.1.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kubevirt.io//2023/changelog-v1.1.0.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="v110">v1.1.0</h2>

<p>Released on: Mon Nov 6 16:28:56 2023 +0000</p>

<ul>
  <li>[PR #10669][kubevirt-bot] Introduce network binding plugin for Passt networking, interfacing with Kubevirt new network binding plugin API.</li>
  <li>[PR #10646][jean-edouard] The dedicated migration network should now always be properly detected by virt-handler</li>
  <li>[PR #10602][kubevirt-bot] Fix LowKVMNodesCount not firing</li>
  <li>[PR #10566][fossedihelm] Add 100Mi of memory overhead for vmi with dedicatedCPU or that wants GuaranteedQos</li>
  <li>[PR #10568][ormergi] Network binding plugin API support CNIs, new integration point on virt-launcher pod creation.</li>
  <li>[PR #10496][fossedihelm] Automatically set cpu limits when a resource quota with cpu limits is associated to the creation namespace and the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">AutoResourceLimits</code> FeatureGate is enabled</li>
  <li>[PR #10309][lyarwood] cluster-wide <a href="https://github.com/kubevirt/common-instancetypes"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">common-instancetypes</code></a> resources can now deployed by <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">virt-operator</code> using the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">CommonInstancetypesDeploymentGate</code> feature gate.</li>
  <li>[PR #10543][0xFelix] Clear VM guest memory when ignoring inference failures</li>
  <li>[PR #9590][xuzhenglun] fix embed version info of virt-operator</li>
  <li>[PR #10532][alromeros] Add –volume-mode flag in image-upload</li>
  <li>[PR #10515][iholder101] Bug-fix: Stop copying VMI spec to VM during snapshots</li>
  <li>[PR #10320][victortoso] sidecar-shim implements PreCloudInitIso hook</li>
  <li>[PR #10463][0xFelix] VirtualMachines: Introduce InferFromVolumeFailurePolicy in Instancetype- and PreferenceMatchers</li>
  <li>[PR #10393][iholder101] [Bugfix] [Clone API] Double-cloning is now working as expected.</li>
  <li>[PR #10486][assafad] Deprecation notice for the metrics listed in the PR. Please update your systems to use the new metrics names.</li>
  <li>[PR #10438][lyarwood] A new <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">instancetype.kubevirt.io:view</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ClusterRole</code> has been introduced that can be bound to users via a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ClusterRoleBinding</code> to provide read only access to the cluster scoped <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachineCluster{Instancetype,Preference}</code> resources.</li>
  <li>[PR #10477][jean-edouard] Dynamic KSM enabling and configuration</li>
  <li>[PR #10110][tiraboschi] Stream guest serial console logs from a dedicated container</li>
  <li>[PR #10015][victortoso] Implements USB host passthrough in permittedHostDevices of KubeVirt CRD</li>
  <li>[PR #10184][acardace] Add memory hotplug feature</li>
  <li>[PR #10044][machadovilaca] Add operator-observability package</li>
  <li>[PR #10489][maiqueb] Remove the network-attachment-definition <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">list</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">watch</code> verbs from virt-controller’s RBAC</li>
  <li>[PR #10450][0xFelix] virtctl: Enable inference in create vm subcommand by default</li>
  <li>[PR #10447][fossedihelm] Add a Feature Gate to KV CR to automatically set memory limits when a resource quota with memory limits is associated to the creation namespace</li>
  <li>[PR #10253][rmohr] Stop trying to create unused directory /var/run/kubevirt-ephemeral-disk in virt-controller</li>
  <li>[PR #10231][kvaps] Propogate public-keys to cloud-init NoCloud meta-data</li>
  <li>[PR #10400][alromeros] Add new vmexport flags to download raw images, either directly (–raw) or by decompressing (–decompress) them</li>
  <li>[PR #9673][germag] DownwardMetrics: Expose DownwardMetrics through virtio-serial channel.</li>
  <li>[PR #10086][vladikr] allow live updating VM affinity and node selector</li>
  <li>[PR #10050][victortoso] Updating the virt stack: QEMU 8.0.0, libvirt to 9.5.0, edk2 20230524,</li>
  <li>[PR #10370][benjx1990] N/A</li>
  <li>[PR #10391][awels] BugFix: VMExport now works in a namespace with quotas defined.</li>
  <li>[PR #10386][liuzhen21] KubeSphere added to the adopter’s file!</li>
  <li>[PR #10380][alromeros] Bugfix: Allow image-upload to recover from PendingPopulation phase</li>
  <li>[PR #10366][ormergi] Kubevirt now delegates Slirp networking configuration to Slirp network binding plugin.  In case you haven’t registered Slirp network binding plugin image yet (i.e.: specify in Kubevirt config) the following default image would be used: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">quay.io/kubevirt/network-slirp-binding:20230830_638c60fc8</code>. On next release (v1.2.0) no default image will be set and registering an image would be mandatory.</li>
  <li>[PR #10167][0xFelix] virtctl: Apply namespace to created manifests</li>
  <li>[PR #10148][alromeros] Add port-forward functionalities to vmexport</li>
  <li>[PR #9821][sradco] Deprecation notice for the metrics listed in the PR. Please update your systems to use the new metrics names.</li>
  <li>[PR #10272][ormergi] Introduce network binding plugin for Slirp networking, interfacing with Kubevirt new network binding plugin API.</li>
  <li>[PR #10284][AlonaKaplan] Introduce an API for network binding plugins. The feature is behind “NetworkBindingPlugins” gate.</li>
  <li>[PR #10275][awels] Ensure new hotplug attachment pod is ready before deleting old attachment pod</li>
  <li>[PR #9231][victortoso] Introduces sidecar-shim container image</li>
  <li>[PR #10254][rmohr] Don’t mark the KubeVirt “Available” condition as false on up-to-date and ready but misscheduled virt-handler pods.</li>
  <li>[PR #10185][AlonaKaplan] Add support to migration based SRIOV hotplug.</li>
  <li>[PR #10182][iholder101] Stop considering nodes without <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kubevirt.io/schedulable</code> label when finding lowest TSC frequency on the cluster</li>
  <li>[PR #10138][machadovilaca] Change kubevirt_vmi_*_usage_seconds from Gauge to Counter</li>
  <li>[PR #10173][rmohr]</li>
  <li>[PR #10101][acardace] Deprecate <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">spec.config.machineType</code> in KubeVirt CR.</li>
  <li>[PR #10020][akalenyu] Use auth API for DataVolumes, stop importing kubevirt.io/containerized-data-importer</li>
  <li>[PR #10107][PiotrProkop] Expose kubevirt_vmi_vcpu_delay_seconds_total reporting amount of seconds VM spent in  waiting in the queue instead of running.</li>
  <li>[PR #10099][iholder101] Bugfix: target virt-launcher pod hangs when migration is cancelled.</li>
  <li>[PR #10056][jean-edouard] UEFI guests now use Bochs display instead of VGA emulation</li>
  <li>[PR #10070][machadovilaca] Remove affinities label from kubevirt_vmi_cpu_affinity and use sum as value</li>
  <li>[PR #10165][awels] BugFix: deleting hotplug attachment pod will no longer detach volumes that were not removed.</li>
  <li>[PR #9878][jean-edouard] The EFI NVRAM can now be configured to persist across reboots</li>
  <li>[PR #9932][lyarwood] <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ControllerRevisions</code> containing <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">instancetype.kubevirt.io</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">CRDs</code> are now decorated with labels detailing specific metadata of the underlying stashed object</li>
  <li>[PR #10039][simonyangcj] fix guaranteed qos of virt-launcher pod broken when use virtiofs</li>
  <li>[PR #10116][ormergi] Existing detached interfaces with ‘absent’ state will be cleared from VMI spec.</li>
  <li>[PR #9982][fabiand] Introduce a support lifecycle and Kubernetes target version.</li>
  <li>[PR #10118][akalenyu] Change exportserver default UID to succeed exporting CDI standalone PVCs (not attached to VM)</li>
  <li>[PR #10106][acardace] Add boot-menu wait time when starting the VM as paused.</li>
  <li>[PR #10058][alicefr] Add field errorPolicy for disks</li>
  <li>[PR #10004][AlonaKaplan] Hoyplug/unplug interfaces should be done by updating the VM spec template. virtctl and REST API endpoints were removed.</li>
  <li>[PR #10067][iholder101] Bug fix: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">virtctl create clone</code> marshalling and replacement of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kubectl</code> with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kubectl virt</code></li>
  <li>[PR #9989][alaypatel07] Add perf scale benchmarks for VMIs</li>
  <li>[PR #10001][machadovilaca] Fix kubevirt_vmi_phase_count not being created</li>
  <li>[PR #9896][ormergi] The VM controller now replicates spec interfaces MAC addresses to the corresponding interfaces in the VMI spec.</li>
  <li>[PR #9840][dhiller] Increase probability for flake checker script to find flakes</li>
  <li>[PR #9988][enp0s3] always deploy the outdated VMI workload alert</li>
  <li>[PR #7708][VirrageS] <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">nodeSelector</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">schedulerName</code> fields have been added to VirtualMachineInstancetype spec.</li>
  <li>[PR #7197][vasiliy-ul] Experimantal support of SEV attestation via the new API endpoints</li>
  <li>[PR #9958][AlonaKaplan] Disable network interface hotplug/unplug for VMIs. It will be supported for VMs only.</li>
  <li>[PR #9882][dhiller] Add some context for initial contributors about automated testing and draft pull requests.</li>
  <li>[PR #9935][xpivarc] Bug fix - correct logging in container disk</li>
  <li>[PR #9552][phoracek] gRPC client now works correctly with non-Go gRPC servers</li>
  <li>[PR #9918][ShellyKa13] Fix for hotplug with WFFC SCI storage class which uses CDI populators</li>
  <li>[PR #9737][AlonaKaplan] On hotunplug - remove bridge, tap and dummy interface from virt-launcher and the caches (file and volatile) from the node.</li>
  <li>[PR #9861][rmohr] Fix the possibility of data corruption when requestin a force-restart via “virtctl restart”</li>
  <li>[PR #9818][akrejcir] Added “virtctl credentials” commands to dynamically change SSH keys in a VM, and to set user’s password.</li>
  <li>[PR #9872][alromeros] Bugfix: Allow lun disks to be mapped to DataVolume sources</li>
  <li>[PR #9073][machadovilaca] Fix incorrect KubevirtVmHighMemoryUsage description</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>kube🤖</name></author><category term="releases" /><category term="release notes" /><category term="changelog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article provides information about KubeVirt release v1.1.0 changes]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KubeVirt v1.0.0</title><link href="https://kubevirt.io//2023/changelog-v1.0.0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KubeVirt v1.0.0" /><published>2023-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kubevirt.io//2023/changelog-v1.0.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kubevirt.io//2023/changelog-v1.0.0.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="v100">v1.0.0</h2>

<p>Released on: Thu Jul 6 17:39:42 2023 +0000</p>

<ul>
  <li>[PR #10037][kubevirt-bot] The VM controller now replicates spec interfaces MAC addresses to the corresponding interfaces in the VMI spec.</li>
  <li>[PR #9992][machadovilaca] Fix incorrect KubevirtVmHighMemoryUsage description</li>
  <li>[PR #9965][kubevirt-bot] Disable network interface hotplug/unplug for VMIs. It will be supported for VMs only.</li>
  <li>[PR #9931][kubevirt-bot] Fix for hotplug with WFFC SCI storage class which uses CDI populators</li>
  <li>[PR #9946][kubevirt-bot] On hotunplug - remove bridge, tap and dummy interface from virt-launcher and the caches (file and volatile) from the node.</li>
  <li>[PR #9757][enp0s3] Introduce CPU hotplug</li>
  <li>[PR #9811][machadovilaca] Remove unnecessary marketplace tool</li>
  <li>[PR #7742][Fuzzy-Math] Experimental support for AMD SEV-ES</li>
  <li>[PR #9799][vladikr] Introduce an ability to set memory overcommit percentage in instanceType spec</li>
  <li>[PR #8780][lyarwood] Add basic support for expressing minimum resource requirements for CPU and Memory within VirtualMachine{Preferences,ClusterPreferences}</li>
  <li>[PR #9812][mhenriks] Handle DataVolume PendingPopulation phase</li>
  <li>[PR #9858][fossedihelm] build virtctl for all os/architectures when <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">KUBEVIRT_RELEASE</code> env var is true</li>
  <li>[PR #9765][lyarwood] Allow to define preferred cpu features in VirtualMachine{Preferences,ClusterPreferences}</li>
  <li>[PR #9844][EdDev] Drop the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kubevirt.io/interface</code> resource name API for reserving domain resources for network interfaces.</li>
  <li>[PR #9841][ormergi] Support hot-unplug of network interfaces on VirtualMachine objects</li>
  <li>[PR #9851][lxs137] virt-api: portfowrad can handle IPv6 VM</li>
  <li>[PR #9845][lxs137] DHCPv6 server handle request without iana option</li>
  <li>[PR #9769][lyarwood] Allow to define the preferred subdomain in VirtualMachine{Preferences,ClusterPreferences}</li>
  <li>[PR #9246][jean-edouard] Fixed migration issue for VMIs that have RWX disks backed by filesystem storage classes.</li>
  <li>[PR #9808][jcanocan] DownwardMetrics: Rename AllocatedToVirtualServers metric to AllocatedToVirtualServers and add ResourceProcessorLimit metric</li>
  <li>[PR #9832][tiraboschi] build virtctl also for arm64 for linux, darwin and windows</li>
  <li>[PR #9744][lyarwood] Allow to define the preferred termination grace period in VirtualMachine{Preferences,ClusterPreferences}</li>
  <li>[PR #9828][rthallisey] Publish multiarch manifests with each release</li>
  <li>[PR #9761][lyarwood] Allow to define the preferred masquerade configuration in VirtualMachine{Preferences,ClusterPreferences}</li>
  <li>[PR #9768][jean-edouard] New CR option to enable auto CPU limits for virt-launcher on some namespaces</li>
  <li>[PR #9779][EdDev] Support hot-unplug of network interfaces on VMI objects</li>
  <li>[PR #9688][xpivarc] Users are warned about the usage of deprecated fields</li>
  <li>[PR #9798][rmohr] Add LiveMigrateIfPossible eviction strategy to allow admins to express a live migration preference instead of a live migration requirement for evictions.</li>
  <li>[PR #9764][fossedihelm] Cluster admins can enable ksm in a set of nodes via kv configuration</li>
  <li>[PR #9753][lyarwood] The following flags have been added to the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">virtctl image-upload</code> command allowing users to associate a default instance type and/or preference with an image during upload. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">--default-instancetype</code>,  <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">--default-instancetype-kind</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">--default-preference</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">--default-preference-kind</code>. <a href="https://kubevirt.io/user-guide/virtual_machines/instancetypes/#inferfromvolume">See the user-guide documentation</a> for more details on using the uploaded image with the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">inferFromVolume</code> feature during <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code> creation.</li>
  <li>[PR #9575][lyarwood] A new <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">v1beta1</code> version of the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">instancetype.kubevirt.io</code> API and CRDs has been introduced.</li>
  <li>[PR #9738][Barakmor1] Add condition to migrations that indicates that migration was rejected by ResourceQuota</li>
  <li>[PR #9730][assafad] Add <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kubevirt_vmi_memory_cached_bytes</code> metric</li>
  <li>[PR #9674][fossedihelm] Introduce cluster configuration <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachineOptions</code> to specify virtual machine behavior at cluster level</li>
  <li>[PR #9724][0xFelix] An alert which triggers when KubeVirt APIs marked as deprecated are used was added.</li>
  <li>[PR #9623][rmohr] Bump to apimachinery 1.26</li>
  <li>[PR #9747][lyarwood] action required - With the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">v1.0.0</code> release of KubeVirt the storage version of all core <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kubevirt.io</code> APIs will be moving to version <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">v1</code>. To accommodate the eventual removal of the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">v1alpha3</code> version with KubeVirt &gt;=<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">v1.2.0</code> it is recommended that operators deploy the <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/kube-storage-version-migrator"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kube-storage-version-migrator</code></a> tool within their environment. This will ensure any existing <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">v1alpha3</code> stored objects are migrated to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">v1</code> well in advance of the removal of the underlying <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">v1alpha3</code> version.</li>
  <li>[PR #9268][ormergi] virt-launcher pods network interfaces name scheme is changed to hashed names (SHA256), based on the VMI spec network names.</li>
  <li>[PR #9746][EdDev] Introduce the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kubevirt.io/interface</code> resource name to reserve domain resources for network interfaces.</li>
  <li>[PR #9652][machadovilaca] Add kubevirt_number_of_vms recording rule</li>
  <li>[PR #9691][fossedihelm] ksm enabled nodes will have <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kubevirt.io/ksm-enabled</code> label</li>
  <li>[PR #9628][lyarwood] * The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kubevirt.io/v1</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">apiVersion</code> is now the default storage version for newly created objects</li>
  <li>[PR #8293][daghaian] Add multi-arch support to KubeVirt. This allows a single KubeVirt installation to run VMs on different node architectures in the same cluster.</li>
  <li>[PR #9686][maiqueb] Fix ownership of macvtap’s char devices on non-root pods</li>
  <li>[PR #9631][0xFelix] virtctl: Allow to infer instancetype or preference from specified volume when creating VMs</li>
  <li>[PR #9665][rmohr] Expose the final resolved qemu machine type on the VMI on status.machine</li>
  <li>[PR #9609][germag] Add support for running virtiofsd in an unprivileged container when sharing configuration volumes.</li>
  <li>[PR #9651][0xFelix] virtctl: Allow to specify memory of created VMs. Default to 512Mi if no instancetype was specified or is inferred.</li>
  <li>[PR #9640][jean-edouard] TSC-enabled VMs can now migrate to a node with a non-identical (but close-enough) frequency</li>
  <li>[PR #9629][0xFelix] virtctl: Allow to specify the boot order of volumes when creating VMs</li>
  <li>[PR #9632][toelke] * Add Genesis Cloud to the adopters list</li>
  <li>[PR #9572][fossedihelm] Enable freePageReporting for new non high performance vmi</li>
  <li>[PR #9435][rmohr] Ensure existence of all PVCs attached to the VMI before creating the VM target pod.</li>
  <li>[PR #8156][jean-edouard] TPM VM device can now be set to persistent</li>
  <li>[PR #8575][iholder101] QEMU-level migration parallelism (a.k.a. multifd) + Upgrade QEMU to 7.2.0-11.el9</li>
  <li>[PR #9603][qinqon] Adapt node-labeller.sh script to work at non kvm envs with emulation.</li>
  <li>[PR #9591][awels] BugFix: allow multiple NFS disks to be used/hotplugged</li>
  <li>[PR #9596][iholder101] Add “virtctl create clone” command</li>
  <li>[PR #9422][awels] Ability to specify cpu/mem request limit for supporting containers (hotplug/container disk/virtiofs/side car)</li>
  <li>[PR #9536][akalenyu] BugFix: virtualmachineclusterinstancetypes/preferences show up for get all -n <namespace></namespace></li>
  <li>[PR #9177][alicefr] Adding SCSI persistent reservation</li>
  <li>[PR #9470][machadovilaca] Enable libvirt GetDomainStats on paused VMs</li>
  <li>[PR #9407][assafad] Use env <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">RUNBOOK_URL_TEMPLATE</code> for the runbooks URL template</li>
  <li>[PR #9399][maiqueb] Compute the interfaces to be hotplugged based on the current domain info, rather than on the interface status.</li>
  <li>[PR #9491][orelmisan] API, AddInterfaceOptions: Rename NetworkName to NetworkAttachmentDefinitionName and InterfaceName to Name</li>
  <li>[PR #9327][jcanocan] DownwardMetrics: Swap KubeVirt build info with qemu version in VirtProductInfo field</li>
  <li>[PR #9478][xpivarc] Bug fix: Fixes case when migration is not retried if the migration Pod gets denied.</li>
  <li>[PR #9421][lyarwood] Requests to update the target <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Name</code> of a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">{Instancetype,Preference}Matcher</code> without also updating the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">RevisionName</code> are now rejected.</li>
  <li>[PR #9367][machadovilaca] Add VM instancetype and preference label to vmi_phase_count metric</li>
  <li>[PR #9392][awels] virtctl supports retrieving vm manifest for VM export</li>
  <li>[PR #9442][EdDev] Remove the VMI Status interface <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">podConfigDone</code> field in favor of a new source option in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">infoSource</code>.</li>
  <li>[PR #9376][ShellyKa13] Fix vmrestore with WFFC snapshotable storage class</li>
  <li>[PR #6852][maiqueb] Dev preview: Enables network interface hotplug for VMs / VMIs</li>
  <li>[PR #9300][xpivarc] Bug fix: API and virtctl invoked migration is not rejected when the VM is paused</li>
  <li>[PR #9189][xpivarc] Bug fix: DNS integration continues to work after migration</li>
  <li>[PR #9322][iholder101] Add guest-to-request memory headroom ratio.</li>
  <li>[PR #8906][machadovilaca] Alert if there are no available nodes to run VMs</li>
  <li>[PR #9320][darfux] node-labeller: Check arch on the handler side</li>
  <li>[PR #9127][fossedihelm] Use ECDSA instead of RSA for key generation</li>
  <li>[PR #9330][qinqon] Skip label kubevirt.io/migrationTargetNodeName from virtctl expose service selector</li>
  <li>[PR #9163][vladikr] fixes the requests/limits CPU number mismatch for VMs with isolatedEmulatorThread</li>
  <li>[PR #9250][vladikr] externally created mediated devices will not be deleted by virt-handler</li>
  <li>[PR #9193][qinqon] Add annotation for live migration and bridged pod interface</li>
  <li>[PR #9260][ShellyKa13] Fix bug of possible re-trigger of memory dump</li>
  <li>[PR #9241][akalenyu] BugFix: Guestfs image url not constructed correctly</li>
  <li>[PR #9220][orelmisan] client-go: Added context to VirtualMachine’s methods.</li>
  <li>[PR #9228][rumans] Bump virtiofs container limit</li>
  <li>[PR #9169][lyarwood] The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dedicatedCPUPlacement</code> attribute is once again supported within the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachineInstancetype</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachineClusterInstancetype</code> CRDs after a recent bugfix improved <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code> validations, ensuring defaults are applied before any attempt to validate.</li>
  <li>[PR #9159][andreabolognani] This version of KubeVirt includes upgraded virtualization technology based on libvirt 9.0.0 and QEMU 7.2.0.</li>
  <li>[PR #8989][rthallisey] Integrate multi-architecture container manifests into the bazel make recipes</li>
  <li>[PR #9188][awels] Default RBAC for clone and export</li>
  <li>[PR #9145][awels] Show VirtualMachine name in the VMExport status</li>
  <li>[PR #8937][fossedihelm] Added foreground finalizer to  virtual machine</li>
  <li>[PR #9133][ShellyKa13] Fix addvolume not rejecting adding existing volume source, fix removevolume allowing to remove non hotpluggable volume</li>
  <li>[PR #9047][machadovilaca] Deprecate VM stuck in status alerts</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>kube🤖</name></author><category term="releases" /><category term="release notes" /><category term="changelog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article provides information about KubeVirt release v1.0.0 changes]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KubeVirt v0.59.0</title><link href="https://kubevirt.io//2023/changelog-v0.59.0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KubeVirt v0.59.0" /><published>2023-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kubevirt.io//2023/changelog-v0.59.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kubevirt.io//2023/changelog-v0.59.0.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="v0590">v0.59.0</h2>

<p>Released on: Wed Mar 1 16:49:27 2023 +0000</p>

<ul>
  <li>[PR #9311][kubevirt-bot] fixes the requests/limits CPU number mismatch for VMs with isolatedEmulatorThread</li>
  <li>[PR #9276][fossedihelm] Added foreground finalizer to  virtual machine</li>
  <li>[PR #9295][kubevirt-bot] Fix bug of possible re-trigger of memory dump</li>
  <li>[PR #9270][kubevirt-bot] BugFix: Guestfs image url not constructed correctly</li>
  <li>[PR #9234][kubevirt-bot] The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dedicatedCPUPlacement</code> attribute is once again supported within the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachineInstancetype</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachineClusterInstancetype</code> CRDs after a recent bugfix improved <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code> validations, ensuring defaults are applied before any attempt to validate.</li>
  <li>[PR #9267][fossedihelm] This version of KubeVirt includes upgraded virtualization technology based on libvirt 9.0.0 and QEMU 7.2.0.</li>
  <li>[PR #9197][kubevirt-bot] Fix addvolume not rejecting adding existing volume source, fix removevolume allowing to remove non hotpluggable volume</li>
  <li>[PR #9120][0xFelix] Fix access to portforwarding on VMs/VMIs with the cluster roles kubevirt.io:admin and kubevirt.io:edit</li>
  <li>[PR #9116][EdDev] Allow the specification of the ACPI Index on a network interface.</li>
  <li>[PR #8774][avlitman] Added new Virtual machines CPU metrics:</li>
  <li>[PR #9087][zhuchenwang] Open <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/dev/vhost-vsock</code> explicitly to ensure that the right vsock module is loaded</li>
  <li>[PR #9020][feitnomore] Adding support for status/scale subresources so that VirtualMachinePool now supports HorizontalPodAutoscaler</li>
  <li>[PR #9085][0xFelix] virtctl: Add options to infer instancetype and preference when creating a VM</li>
  <li>[PR #8917][xpivarc] Kubevirt can be configured with Seccomp profile. It now ships a custom profile for the launcher.</li>
  <li>[PR #9054][enp0s3] do not inject LimitRange defaults into VMI</li>
  <li>[PR #7862][vladikr] Store the finalized VMI migration status in the migration objects.</li>
  <li>[PR #8878][0xFelix] Add ‘create vm’ command to virtctl</li>
  <li>[PR #9048][jean-edouard] DisableCustomSELinuxPolicy feature gate introduced to disable our custom SELinux policy</li>
  <li>[PR #8953][awels] VMExport now has endpoint containing entire VM definition.</li>
  <li>[PR #8976][iholder101] Fix podman CRI detection</li>
  <li>[PR #9043][iholder101] Adjust operator functional tests to custom images specification</li>
  <li>[PR #8875][machadovilaca] Rename migration metrics removing ‘total’ keyword</li>
  <li>[PR #9040][lyarwood] <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">inferFromVolume</code> now uses labels instead of annotations to lookup default instance type and preference details from a referenced <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Volume</code>. This has changed in order to provide users with a way of looking up suitably decorated resources through these labels before pointing to them within the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code>.</li>
  <li>[PR #9039][orelmisan] client-go: Added context to additional VirtualMachineInstance’s methods.</li>
  <li>[PR #9018][orelmisan] client-go: Added context to additional VirtualMachineInstance’s methods.</li>
  <li>[PR #9025][akalenyu] BugFix: Hotplug pods have hardcoded resource req which don’t comply with LimitRange maxLimitRequestRatio of 1</li>
  <li>[PR #8908][orelmisan] client-go: Added context to some of VirtualMachineInstance’s methods.</li>
  <li>[PR #6863][rmohr] The install strategy job will respect the infra node placement from now on</li>
  <li>[PR #8948][iholder101] Bugfix: virt-handler socket leak</li>
  <li>[PR #8649][acardace] KubeVirt is now able to run VMs inside restricted namespaces.</li>
  <li>[PR #8992][iholder101] Align with k8s fix for default limit range requirements</li>
  <li>[PR #8889][rmohr] Add basic TLS encryption support for vsock websocket connections</li>
  <li>[PR #8660][huyinhou] Fix remoteAddress field in virt-api log being truncated when it is an ipv6 address</li>
  <li>[PR #8961][rmohr] Bump distroless base images</li>
  <li>[PR #8952][rmohr] Fix read-only sata disk validation</li>
  <li>[PR #8657][fossedihelm] Use an increasingly exponential backoff before retrying to start the VM, when an I/O error occurs.</li>
  <li>[PR #8480][lyarwood] New <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">inferFromVolume</code> attributes have been introduced to the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">{Instancetype,Preference}Matchers</code> of a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code>. When provided the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Volume</code> referenced by the attribute is checked for the following annotations with which to populate the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">{Instancetype,Preference}Matchers</code>:</li>
  <li>[PR #7762][VirrageS] Service <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kubevirt-prometheus-metrics</code> now sets <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ClusterIP</code> to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">None</code> to make it a headless service.</li>
  <li>[PR #8599][machadovilaca] Change KubevirtVmHighMemoryUsage threshold from 20MB to 50MB</li>
  <li>[PR #7761][VirrageS] imagePullSecrets field has been added to KubeVirt CR to support deployments form private registries</li>
  <li>[PR #8887][iholder101] Bugfix: use virt operator image if provided</li>
  <li>[PR #8750][jordigilh] Fixes an issue that prevented running real time workloads in non-root configurations due to libvirt’s dependency on CAP_SYS_NICE to change the vcpu’s thread’s scheduling and priority to FIFO and 1. The change of priority and scheduling is now executed in the virt-launcher for both root and non-root configurations, removing the dependency in libvirt.</li>
  <li>[PR #8845][lyarwood] An empty <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Timer</code> is now correctly omitted from <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Clock</code> fixing bug #8844.</li>
  <li>[PR #8842][andreabolognani] The virt-launcher pod no longer needs the SYS_PTRACE capability.</li>
  <li>[PR #8734][alicefr] Change libguestfs-tools image using root appliance in qcow2 format</li>
  <li>[PR #8764][ShellyKa13] Add list of included and excluded volumes in vmSnapshot</li>
  <li>[PR #8811][iholder101] Custom components: support gs</li>
  <li>[PR #8770][dhiller] Add Ginkgo V2 Serial decorator to serial tests as preparation to simplify parallel vs. serial test run logic</li>
  <li>[PR #8808][acardace] Apply migration backoff only for evacuation migrations.</li>
  <li>[PR #8525][jean-edouard] CR option mediatedDevicesTypes is deprecated in favor of mediatedDeviceTypes</li>
  <li>[PR #8792][iholder101] Expose new custom components env vars to csv-generator and manifest-templator</li>
  <li>[PR #8701][enp0s3] Consider the ParallelOutboundMigrationsPerNode when evicting VMs</li>
  <li>[PR #8740][iholder101] Fix: Align Reenlightenment flows between converter.go and template.go</li>
  <li>[PR #8530][acardace] Use exponential backoff for failing migrations</li>
  <li>[PR #8720][0xFelix] The expand-spec subresource endpoint was renamed to expand-vm-spec and made namespaced</li>
  <li>[PR #8458][iholder101] Introduce support for clones with a snapshot source (e.g. clone snapshot -&gt; VM)</li>
  <li>[PR #8716][rhrazdil] Add overhead of interface with Passt binding when no ports are specified</li>
  <li>[PR #8619][fossedihelm] virt-launcher: use <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">virtqemud</code> daemon instead of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">libvirtd</code></li>
  <li>[PR #8736][knopt] Added more precise rest_client_request_latency_seconds histogram buckets</li>
  <li>[PR #8624][zhuchenwang] Add the REST API to be able to talk to the application in the guest VM via VSOCK.</li>
  <li>[PR #8625][AlonaKaplan] iptables are no longer used by masquerade binding. Nodes with iptables only won’t be able to run VMs with masquerade binding.</li>
  <li>[PR #8673][iholder101] Allow specifying custom images for core components</li>
  <li>[PR #8622][jean-edouard] Built with golang 1.19</li>
  <li>[PR #8336][alicefr] Flag for setting the guestfs uid and gid</li>
  <li>[PR #8667][huyinhou] connect VM vnc failed when virt-launcher work directory is not /</li>
  <li>[PR #8368][machadovilaca] Use collector to set migration metrics</li>
  <li>[PR #8558][xpivarc] Bug-fix: LimitRange integration now works when VMI is missing namespace</li>
  <li>[PR #8404][andreabolognani] This version of KubeVirt includes upgraded virtualization technology based on libvirt 8.7.0, QEMU 7.1.0 and CentOS Stream 9.</li>
  <li>[PR #8652][akalenyu] BugFix: Exporter pod does not comply with restricted PSA</li>
  <li>[PR #8563][xpivarc] Kubevirt now runs with nonroot user by default</li>
  <li>[PR #8442][kvaps] Add Deckhouse to the Adopters list</li>
  <li>[PR #8546][zhuchenwang] Provides the Vsock feature for KubeVirt VMs.</li>
  <li>[PR #8598][acardace] VMs configured with hugepages can now run using the default container_t SELinux type</li>
  <li>[PR #8594][kylealexlane] Fix permission denied on on selinux relabeling on some kernel versions</li>
  <li>[PR #8521][akalenyu] Add an option to specify a TTL for VMExport objects</li>
  <li>[PR #7918][machadovilaca] Add alerts for VMs unhealthy states</li>
  <li>[PR #8516][rhrazdil] When using Passt binding, virl-launcher has unprivileged_port_start set to 0, so that passt may bind to all ports.</li>
  <li>[PR #7772][jean-edouard] The SELinux policy for virt-launcher is down to 4 rules, 1 for hugepages and 3 for virtiofs.</li>
  <li>[PR #8402][jean-edouard] Most VMIs now run under the SELinux type container_t</li>
  <li>[PR #8513][alromeros] [Bug-fix] Fix error handling in virtctl image-upload</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>kube🤖</name></author><category term="releases" /><category term="release notes" /><category term="changelog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article provides information about KubeVirt release v0.59.0 changes]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KubeVirt v0.58.0</title><link href="https://kubevirt.io//2022/changelog-v0.58.0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KubeVirt v0.58.0" /><published>2022-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kubevirt.io//2022/changelog-v0.58.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kubevirt.io//2022/changelog-v0.58.0.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="v0580">v0.58.0</h2>

<p>Released on: Thu Oct 13 00:24:51 2022 +0000</p>

<ul>
  <li>[PR #8578][rhrazdil] When using Passt binding, virl-launcher has unprivileged_port_start set to 0, so that passt may bind to all ports.</li>
  <li>[PR #8463][Barakmor1] Improve metrics documentation</li>
  <li>[PR #8282][akrejcir] Improves instancetype and preference controller revisions. This is a backwards incompatible change and introduces a new v1alpha2 api for instancetype and preferences.</li>
  <li>[PR #8272][jean-edouard] No more empty section in the kubevirt-cr manifest</li>
  <li>[PR #8536][qinqon] Don’t show a failure if ConfigDrive cloud init has UserDataSecretRef and not NetworkDataSecretRef</li>
  <li>[PR #8375][xpivarc] Virtiofs can be used with Nonroot feature gate</li>
  <li>[PR #8465][rmohr] Add a vnc screenshot REST endpoint and a “virtctl vnc screenshot” command for UI and script integration</li>
  <li>[PR #8418][alromeros] Enable automatic token generation for VirtualMachineExport objects</li>
  <li>[PR #8488][0xFelix] virtctl: Be less verbose when using the local ssh client</li>
  <li>[PR #8396][alicefr] Add group flag for setting the gid and fsgroup in guestfs</li>
  <li>[PR #8476][iholder-redhat] Allow setting virt-operator log verbosity through Kubevirt CR</li>
  <li>[PR #8366][rthallisey] Move KubeVirt to a 15 week release cadence</li>
  <li>[PR #8479][arnongilboa] Enable DataVolume GC by default in cluster-deploy</li>
  <li>[PR #8474][vasiliy-ul] Fixed migration failure of VMs with containerdisks on systems with containerd</li>
  <li>[PR #8316][ShellyKa13] Fix possible race when deleting unready vmsnapshot and the vm remaining frozen</li>
  <li>[PR #8436][xpivarc] Kubevirt is able to run with restricted Pod Security Standard enabled with an automatic escalation of namespace privileges.</li>
  <li>[PR #8197][alromeros] Add vmexport command to virtctl</li>
  <li>[PR #8252][fossedihelm] Add <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">tlsConfiguration</code> to Kubevirt Configuration</li>
  <li>[PR #8431][rmohr] Fix shadow status updates and periodic status updates on VMs, performed by the snapshot controller</li>
  <li>[PR #8359][iholder-redhat] [Bugfix]: HyperV Reenlightenment VMIs should be able to start when TSC Frequency is not exposed</li>
  <li>[PR #8330][jean-edouard] Important: If you use docker with SELinux enabled, set the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DockerSELinuxMCSWorkaround</code> feature gate before upgrading</li>
  <li>[PR #8401][machadovilaca] Rename metrics to follow the naming convention</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>kube🤖</name></author><category term="releases" /><category term="release notes" /><category term="changelog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article provides information about KubeVirt release v0.58.0 changes]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KubeVirt v0.57.0</title><link href="https://kubevirt.io//2022/changelog-v0.57.0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KubeVirt v0.57.0" /><published>2022-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kubevirt.io//2022/changelog-v0.57.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kubevirt.io//2022/changelog-v0.57.0.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="v0570">v0.57.0</h2>

<p>Released on: Mon Sep 12 14:00:44 2022 +0000</p>

<ul>
  <li>[PR #8129][mlhnono68] Fixes virtctl to support connection to clusters proxied by RANCHER or having special paths</li>
  <li>[PR #8337][0xFelix] virtctl’s native SSH client is now useable in the Windows console without workarounds</li>
  <li>[PR #8257][awels] VirtualMachineExport now supports VM export source type.</li>
  <li>[PR #8367][vladikr] fix the guest memory conversion by setting it to resources.requests.memory when guest memory is not explicitly provided</li>
  <li>[PR #7990][ormergi] Deprecate SR-IOV live migration feature gate.</li>
  <li>[PR #8069][lyarwood] The VirtualMachineInstancePreset resource has been deprecated ahead of removal in a future release. Users should instead use the VirtualMachineInstancetype and VirtualMachinePreference resources to encapsulate any shared resource or preferences characteristics shared by their VirtualMachines.</li>
  <li>[PR #8326][0xFelix] virtctl: Do not log wrapped ssh command by default</li>
  <li>[PR #8325][rhrazdil] Enable route_localnet sysctl option for masquerade binding at virt-handler</li>
  <li>[PR #8159][acardace] Add support for USB disks</li>
  <li>[PR #8006][lyarwood] <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">AutoattachInputDevice</code> has been added to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Devices</code> allowing an <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Input</code> device to be automatically attached to a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code> on start up.  <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">PreferredAutoattachInputDevice</code> has also been added to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DevicePreferences</code> allowing users to control this behaviour with a set of preferences.</li>
  <li>[PR #8134][arnongilboa] Support DataVolume garbage collection</li>
  <li>[PR #8157][StefanKro] TrilioVault for Kubernetes now supports KubeVirt for backup and recovery.</li>
  <li>[PR #8273][alaypatel07] add server-side validations for spec.topologySpreadConstraints during object creation</li>
  <li>[PR #8049][alicefr] Set RunAsNonRoot as default for the guestfs pod</li>
  <li>[PR #8107][awels] Allow VirtualMachineSnapshot as a VirtualMachineExport source</li>
  <li>[PR #7846][janeczku] Added support for configuring topology spread constraints for virtual machines.</li>
  <li>[PR #8215][alaypatel07] support validation for spec.affinity fields during vmi creation</li>
  <li>[PR #8071][oshoval] Relax networkInterfaceMultiqueue semantics: multi queue will configure only what it can (virtio interfaces).</li>
  <li>[PR #7549][akrejcir] Added new API subresources to expand instancetype and preference.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>kube🤖</name></author><category term="releases" /><category term="release notes" /><category term="changelog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article provides information about KubeVirt release v0.57.0 changes]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KubeVirt v0.56.0</title><link href="https://kubevirt.io//2022/changelog-v0.56.0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KubeVirt v0.56.0" /><published>2022-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kubevirt.io//2022/changelog-v0.56.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kubevirt.io//2022/changelog-v0.56.0.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="v0560">v0.56.0</h2>

<p>Released on: Thu Aug 18 20:10:29 2022 +0000</p>

<ul>
  <li>[PR #7599][iholder-redhat] Introduce a mechanism to abort non-running migrations - fixes “Unable to cancel live-migration if virt-launcher pod in pending state” bug</li>
  <li>[PR #8027][alaypatel07] Wait deletion to succeed all the way till objects are finalized in perfscale tests</li>
  <li>[PR #8198][rmohr] Improve path handling for non-root virt-launcher workloads</li>
  <li>[PR #8136][iholder-redhat] Fix cgroups unit tests: mock out underlying runc cgroup manager</li>
  <li>[PR #8047][iholder-redhat] Deprecate live migration feature gate</li>
  <li>[PR #7986][iholder-redhat] [Bug-fix]: Windows VM with WSL2 guest fails to migrate</li>
  <li>[PR #7814][machadovilaca] Add VMI filesystem usage metrics</li>
  <li>[PR #7849][AlonaKaplan] [TECH PREVIEW] Introducing passt - a new approach to user-mode networking for virtual machines</li>
  <li>[PR #7991][ShellyKa13] Virtctl memory dump with create flag to create a new pvc</li>
  <li>[PR #8039][lyarwood] The flavor API and associated CRDs of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine{Flavor,ClusterFlavor}</code> are renamed to instancetype and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine{Instancetype,ClusterInstancetype}</code>.</li>
  <li>[PR #8112][AlonaKaplan] Changing the default of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">virtctl expose</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ip-family</code> parameter to be empty value instead of IPv4.</li>
  <li>[PR #8073][orenc1] Bump runc to v1.1.2</li>
  <li>[PR #8092][Barakmor1] Bump the version of emicklei/go-restful from 2.15.0 to 2.16.0</li>
  <li>[PR #8053][alromeros] [Bug-fix]: Fix mechanism to fetch fs overhead when CDI resource has a different name</li>
  <li>[PR #8035][0xFelix] Add option to wrap local scp client to scp command</li>
  <li>[PR #7981][lyarwood] Conflicts will now be raised when using flavors if the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VirtualMachine</code> defines any <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">CPU</code> or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Memory</code> resource requests.</li>
  <li>[PR #8068][awels] Set cache mode to match regular disks on hotplugged disks.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>kube🤖</name></author><category term="releases" /><category term="release notes" /><category term="changelog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article provides information about KubeVirt release v0.56.0 changes]]></summary></entry></feed>